Charles Marttinen.ca

2593 Lundin Dr, Vanderhoof BC mail@charlesmarttinen.ca 705-770-4095

Summary

Full-stack developer experienced in designing and building web applications and APIs in JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Node, Python, and PHP.

Skills

- Browser: JavaScript, TypeScript, IndexedDB, jQuery, custom HTML elements, React, React Router, Redux, HTML, CSS/SCSS, GraphQL
- **Server:** Node, Python (Django), PHP (Symfony Framework), REST APIs
- **SQL** (Postgres and Oracle)
- Accessible HTML design and screen reader testing
- Git and GitHub
- XML: XML Schema, XPath
- UI design focusing on usability and UX
- Vector graphics and logos
- Adobe suite: Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, XD
- Microsoft Office suite

Projects

Verse: versereader.netlify.app

...is a web-based single-page reader app for viewing collections of verse, like books of songs and poems. It offers rapid navigation, page display customization, intuitive search and find features, and good accessibility. (February 2023)

Built with: React, TypeScript, React Router (with form-based loaders and actions), custom HTML elements, IndexedDB, CSS/SCSS, XML (XML Schema, XPath).

Pokémon Finder: pokemon-finder.netlify.app

...is a proof of concept for a dynamic browser-based reporting application for analysing data from the popular video game *Pokémon*. (March 2019)

Built with: React, TypeScript, a GraphQL API based on the open source PokéAPI project, Apollo-GraphQL, Redux, Python, Docker.

Education

Georgian College of Applied Arts and Technology Barrie, Ontario

Diploma in Graphic Design Production, May 2018

Experience

Carpenter at Marttinen Finish Carpentry

Barrie, Ontario, July 2017-August 2023

Custom finish carpentry with a focus on excellent quality and attention to detail.

Core contributor for PokéAPI: <u>pokeapi.co</u> 2017–2019

PokéAPI is an open source REST API for Pokémon data. I re-built the website, fielded support requests and helped transition the former dynamically-served REST API to the current static API.

JavaScript, React, Python, Django, Firebase, Docker.

Software Programmer at Port of Wilmington

Wilmington, Delaware, March 2015–May 2016

Created applications for use by internal staff and outside customers using PHP, Symfony Framework, Oracle SQL, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript:

- Started long-term rebuild of company's legacy
 PHP-based Intranet platform
- Trialled forklift-mounted tablet system for managing pallet movements in the warehouse
- Trialled mobile web app for tracking shipping container movements on and off ships and in the field, for use by field personnel

Facilities Generalist for The City of Barrie

(March 2014–March 2015)

Cleaned two public buildings and handled minor repairs.

Carpenter at Marttinen Finish Carpentry

Barrie, Ontario, 2010-2014